21diamonds.in 2012-10-05

# Online Diamonds Jewellery shopping - Privacy Policy of

## Privacy Policy ** _ ___**

We value your trust immensely. Accordingly, we have framed a privacy policy to keep your transactions and identity secured. Below stated policy will help you understand the system better.

### **1\. Compilation of Personal Data and its Usage**

Your personal information such as name, email address, phone number etc. is collected to setup a free account with 21Diamonds “Us”. All such dealings are kept confidential at our backend and processed for further usage, when dealing with third party. It makes things easy for you to buy products and to complete the payment process. Data assimilation helps to carry out research on our users’ demographics and tracking of sales data.

Through this process we aim to keep you updated with our newsletters and offers. Also, all your questions and problems can be sorted out easily. It helps to organize various surveys which can help in the advancement of site.

### **2\. Cookies and Google Analytics:**

Cookie is a set of defined information which helps to track and recognize a customer. It does not contain any personal detailing nor is it harmful to your system. The information generated by the cookies about your use of this site is send to a Google server in the U.S. and stored there. Links with an IP address and so a link to a specific user, is however not included in the data sent to Google Analytics, because it is first organized.

Google Inc. will use this anonymized information to evaluate use of the website for the purpose of bringing together reports of our website activity, as well as the website use and internet use of related services. Also, Google Inc. may provide such information to third parties, provided it is required by law or if third party or third parties process the information on behalf of Google Inc. Google will not associate the obtained data with other data of Google Inc. Most browsers accept cookies by default. You can deactivate this default setting in the security settings of your internet browser, where you can also delete stored cookies. If you disable cookies altogether, however, some features on our site might not be available (e.g. shopping), and some web-pages may not display properly.  

You can opt-out of data collection by Google Analytics by downloading and installing Google's Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on which is available [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).  The Add-on communicates with the Good Analytics JavaScript (ga.js) to indicate that information about the website should not be sent to Google Analytics. Please note, that this Add-on does not prevent information from being sent to the website itself or other web analytics service, or prevent other Search Engines collecting data. 

### **3\. Login and Security**

Each time you Login to your customer account in 21 Diamonds, data is recorded in a log file. Information like host name, IP address, status, data volume, time etc are stored with us.

We do not associate with any individual users for the data stored in the server log which relates to page views or usages. Storage of IP address is done to block any harm to our website.

### **4\. Social Networking Site Links**

The plug-in of various social networking sites are marked with a Logo. As soon as you click these logos, the browser will directly connect you to our social media page.

Additionally, if you are logged into a social networking site when you visit our site (21Diamonds), Social Media site is able to associate your visit with your account on it. When you interact with the plug-in by, for example, making a comment via a plug-in, the corresponding information is sent directly from your browser and stored by that Social Networking site.

Your personal account information is managed by the networking site data protection policy and it has no links with our backend. If you do not wish any site like Face book to connect the data it has collected about your visit to our site with your Face book account, you must log-out of your Face book account before visiting our site.  

### **5\. Newsletter**

If you would like to subscribe to our newsletter, we will need a valid e-mail address, as well as information that allow us to verify that you are the owner of the e-mail address or that the owner of the e-mail address agrees to the subscription. Further information will not be collected. You can revoke at any time your consent to our storage of relevant data, your e-mail address and our right to send our newsletter.

### **6**. **Right to Opt-Out**

Every member of 21Diamond has the right to stop or opt out receiving newsletters or other promotional mails whenever they feel like. User just need to select the unsubscribe option

For further information about our Data Protection Policy, please contact us by e-mail at [care@21diamonds.in](mailto:care@21diamonds.in)

Please **** Note: Kindly review this policy periodically as it is subject to change anytime without prior notice.
